Ghrisslich

Creative Technologist, Wordpress Engineer, Designer, Teacher

Chris is an excellent Wordpress full-stack developer with a strong design foundation. This allows him to do high-value technical work, with a perfectionist eye for user experience and user interface design.

He's fast learner, and a hard worker. He prides himself on being able to adapt quickly to face new design or development challenges and master ever-changing technologies and trends.

Technical Experience

Javascript: React w/NextJS, Typescript, Vue 2&3, "vanilla" javascript, Node, Express, GSAP, CreateJS, Pixi

CSS: Grid, Flex, Float, Bootstrap, Material, BEM

PHP: Wordpress (classic and Gutenberg), OOP "vanilla" PHP, Laravel

Design Software: XD, Figma, After Effects, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign

Other: Unity Game Engine, Arduino C++, Apple ARKit

Professional Experience

Perficient Inc, 2022-Present

Senior Technical Consultant / Front End Developer

Lead a team with on and offshore developers in React, Vue, and vanilla JS projects, connected to the Optimizely CMS.

Consulted, estimated, collaborated with clients and design teams.

Creative Circus, 2013-2022

Program Director

Directed two two-year portfolio programs: Creative Technology and Graphic Design. Primarily teaching, curriculum development, mentoring.

Taught web development from "hello world" to Wordpress, React, Vue. Taught creative technology from brainstorm to build. Taught graphic design from pencil to print.

Freelance, 2006-Present

Design and Development work, primarily websites, for small to medium size companies. Primarily Wordpress, some Laravel

Primal Screen, 2008-2013

Interactive Director

Worked on a broad spectrum of projects for television advertising, websites, web apps, mobile devices, touchscreens UI. Motion graphics, user experience design, Flash animation, web design and programming, game design and programming.

Portfolio

https://chrissilich.com

Education

Georgia State University Atlanta, Georgia Bachelor of Fine Arts Graphic Design, 2009

Accomplishments

One **Emmy** Nomination, Interactive Media Category Two **SEED** Design Awards Web Design Category #1 Dad Mug

Contact

678-851-1069 chris.silich@gmail.com https://chrissilich.com